なるほど　ニッグは そのアナグラムってわけね。
I have you to thank. I've been like this since I woke up.
多分　俺は赤ん坊の頃 ジンと一緒に　ここに来た。
Don't say that there's nothing you can do.
ジンはきっと 俺に　こう言いたかったんだ。 「何を捨てても俺に会いたいなら
If I can do anything to help Gon, I'll be happy to.
このゲームをクリアするくらい 強くなれ」。
But you must not forget...
で　ジンに会ったら まず　何をする？ もちろん　キルアを紹介するよ。
You are the one Gon needs most.
クレイジースロット　いい目が出ろよ！ トゥルルルル…　４！ クソっ　ハズレだ。
Having escaped the cage of smoke, Pouf had confirmed that Knuckle
and Morel had made contact.
うっせぇ！ ありがたく使え　この野郎！
He decided to assume
え？　アリ？ ケガはないか？
That was the correct call. The boss told me that you could make clones.
ジンじゃ　ない。 え？
Since Knuckle was here, that meant that Youpi had spared his life
おい　何のつもりだよ　あんた。
and had not told Pouf this.
いきなり　ひとを突き飛ばすわ 銃を向けて　ぶっ放すわ 冗談にも程があるぜ！
Depending on his reason...
俺が撃ち殺さなければ お前達が襲われていた。
Answer me!
誰にだよ!? あんたが撃った　このアリにか？
To satisfy him.
何だ　こいつ！ バカ野郎！
Pouf needed to leave the room peacefully
so that he could persuade Knuckle
あ…。
I told you in order to satisfy him.
こいつは　ただのアリじゃ　ない キメラアントだ。 「キメラアント」？
He has demanded that I not leave this room.
第一級隔離指定種に 認定されている 肉食の獰猛な虫だ。
If we are to engage in a duel, I will need him to withdraw his
demand, so that I may leave.
そうやって 人間を襲うことだってある。
I am but a clone...
さっき　お前らが立っていたのは そいつらの巣の真ん前だ。
I cannot use my wing scales.
俺が撃たなきゃ　２人共　今頃
However, I am still willing to fight you.
キメラアントの大群に 全身　食い破られてたんだぞ。
What I seek is a discussion.
これ　何か　前にも…。 ふぅ…。 大丈夫だ　大したことはない。
Pouf knew that when dealing with someone who
would call him from behind to challenge him, appearing to be telling the truth
would be more effective.
何だ　もう終わりか？ もっと派手にやろうぜ！
You're lying...
うるさい　さっさと消えろ。 お前らも　さっさと消えてくれ。
You were going to kill me from behind.
クソっ　邪魔が入ったせいで イチから　やり直しだ。
You even admitted it.
…つっても 巣は破壊しちまったしな。 まったく 余計な殺生させられたぜ。
Knuckle, don't let him fool you!
あっ！ え？ ん？
First, you claim to be a clone.
もしかして…。
This boy is proving troublesome.
もしかして　あの時 俺を助けてくれた人？ あの時？ くじら島で
I dare say that, of our enemies,
he possesses the strongest will.
俺が子連れのキツネグマの 縄張に入り込んじゃって。 くじら島？
Perhaps I should be pleased
その時も　俺のせいで 余計な殺生をしたって…。
that he is trapped here with Pitou.
なるほど　面影がある。
Were I to prove myself a clone, I would
be placing myself at a disadvantage.
まさか　こんな所で また会うとはな。
So I can say nothing.
デッカくなったな　ゴン。
You must use your own judgment.
どうして　俺の名前を？
And...
お前の親父に聞いたんだ ジンさんに。 え？ おじさん　ジンのこと知ってるの？
I shall allow you
おじ…。
to decide what happens next.
ああ　俺の名はカイト ジンさんは俺の師匠だ。
Pouf, you can't mean to...
ほう　それじゃあ　お前達も プロのハンターってわけか。 うん　カイトさんも？
Please wait...
カイトでいいさ　師匠の子に 「さん」付けされるのは照れくさい。
I'm still here! I apologize for Pouf's behavior!
うん　じゃあ　カイトも？
I'm the only one you need, right?
ああ　俺を一人前のハンターに してくれたのは　ジンさんだ。
Ten minutes.
あの人は俺の師匠であり　恩人。 ジンさんに出会わなければ 俺は　とっくの昔に
You have ten fewer minutes to heal her.
待て　コラ！ クソガキが！
How long do I have to wait?
俺が　せっかく見つけたパンを 横取りしやがって！
To completely heal her
今日という今日は 逃がさねえ！
will take three to four hours. No, I can't wait that long.
あ！
Originally, to protect Komugi
and heal her completely, Pitou had deliberately named a longer
time frame than was necessary, which Gon had denied. So the hour that they'd agreed
upon was the actual time
あっ　俺のパンを！ てめぇ　今日は逃がさねえぞ！
Pitou believed necessary for Komugi
to make a full recovery.
うわっ　痛っ！ 何だこいつ　何しやがんだ！ やめろ！　うわ！
However, Doctor Blythe had grown stronger over time.
ん？　お前　こいつらと 一緒に暮らしてんのか。
The King is to the south.
それが　ジンとの出会い？ ああ。 ジンさんが言うには
Gon and Killua had seen everything
that had transpired. But since Pitou did not know that, it was only natural to assume that Gon
いいハンターってやつは 動物に好かれるそうだ。
had seen through Pouf's plans.
「お前には才能があるかもな」って 言われて　その気になってな。
Pitou's worst fears had been confirmed.
んで　弟子に？ 半ば強引にな。 あの人は面倒なことは とことん嫌がる性格だから
Pitou was now fully resolved to
complete the mission at hand.
そうしているうちに 俺の念能力も開発され
I must kill him.
ハントのイロハも叩き込まれた。
No matter the cost! I must kill him...
おかげで ハンター試験そのものは
For the King's sake!
ほとんど苦労なく クリアしたんだが ジンさんに認めてもらうには
Do I move as soon as Komugi is healed?
もう一つ　課題を クリアしなければならなかった。
No, that won't work. I can't expose her to danger.
どんな課題を出されたと思う？
First, I must entrust her to someone else.
何となく　分かる。 ほう。
Pouf and Youpi dislike Komugi.
ううん　何となくじゃ　ない。
This won't do.
ジンなら　きっと こう言ったと思う。 「俺を捕まえてみろ」って。
If I'm gone, who will take Komugi to the King?
その通り　当たりだ。
Gon, I understand what you're saying.
やっぱり！　だと思った。
However...
だが相手は　俺の知る限り 世界最高のハンターだ。
I will still do things my way.
これが　どんな狩りより難しい。
Youpi is...
あの人は　この世から 自分という存在を 完全に消し去っていた。
No, never mind.
超人的な「絶」ってことか それで…　それで　どうしたの？ ほとほと困った俺は
If Knuckle's information made Gon hesitant, it could result in his death.
少しでも 手掛かりを得たいと思ってな
See ya.
あの人の故郷に向かったんだ。 くじら島に。 お前と出会ったのは その時だよ　ゴン。
Knuckle managed to stop himself.
くじら島での出来事を 彼に話した時だ。
How would you know my name?
((そいつは俺のガキだ 名前はゴン))
My subordinates were present at the
moment of your mother's passing.
)
And my subordinates may have died
fighting your Royal Guard by now.
奴らの縄張に入っちゃいけない ってことは　常識だからな))
Interested in fighting me now?
あぁ…。 俺が　くじら島に行ったことも そこで　ゴンに会ったことも ジンさんは驚かなかった。
If you can force me to admit defeat, I will tell you your name.
まるで　俺が　そうすると 分かっていたように。 今　思えば　全てはジンさんの 筋書き通りだったのかもしれない。
Force you to admit defeat without killing you?
最初から　仕組まれてたってこと？ 確証は　ないがな。
So, similar to a bishop and rook handicap...
ドゥーンとリストも。
No matter.
レイザー？　ドゥーン？
I shall checkmate you shortly.
((したら　遠慮しねえで ぶっ飛ばせよ)) ((フッ　じゃあ 殺してもいいってことかよ)) )
As the King moved into his stance, Netero took to the air.
もしかしたら　ビスケや 他の仲間達と出会ったことも
When was it...
全部　計画通りだったんじゃないか って。 もし　そうだとしたら ここでカイトに会うことも ジンが　あらかじめ 決めてたことなのかもしれないな。
that I began to wait for my opponent to attack?
え？ あっ　そうだ！
Whenever you're ready, come at me.
((できるけど… 何で　そんなことするの？)) ((「マグネティックフォース」を使って １人で来るなら
Ninety-ninth Hand!
「達」っていうか　ゴン。 俺は　こいつに くっついて来ただけだから。
When was it
俺も？　いやいや それは　あり得ねえだろ。 だが　ここで俺と出会ったのは どうやら偶然じゃないらしい。
that I stopped hesitating to be gracious, taking the hands of vanquished opponents
ああ　それは俺も　そう思う。 このことには　もっと意味がある。 意味？
when they bowed their heads in defeat?
レイザーがゴンを鍛えるために ゲーム内で待っていたように ジンは　きっとカイトにも
That cannot be
何か役割を与えてると考えるのが 普通だろ？
the ultimate power I sought!
自分の存在を隠すすべにも 長けてる。
It is fighting with all my soul against
それを見つけ出したんだから。 あぁ　うん　俺も　そう思う。
an opponent with the strength to defeat me!
二首オオカミの繁殖方法の確立？
This is a tomb.
ああ　ジンさんの ハンターとしての活動は
Your tomb.
足りぬ　こんなものでは いくら食べても しかし　動けぬ
I am very thankful.
まずは　体を癒やし それからだ
Thankful for everything